Guide to the John Wesley Hardin Papers
The Wittliff Collections
1894 Letters: Recently released from prison, Hardin is involved in prolific correspondence with various persons including sheriffs, attorneys, and local merchants. Of peculiar interest are several bills Hardin received from J.P. Randle, P. Levyson, and (responding to a request for a law book catalogue) Gilbert Book Company.
1895 Letters: One singular article of interest here is Hardin's business card—as an attorney at law in El Paso. The card is fixed to a note, which reads, "This card and about 80 others were found in Hardin's room after he was killed in 1895." One humorous letter dated July 11, from J.H. Flynth, asks Hardin to "please tell me when you was convicted the first time and what was your sentence […] for the purpose of settling a dispute here in regard to the matter." This was answered in a script that (to this writer) appears to be J.W. Hardin's, but was written "in regard to Mr. Hardin," and is unsigned.
Correspondents and Index
Not all names have been indexed. First names without surnames which cannot be otherwise identified or are merely mentioned in passing are not indexed. A question mark in brackets means the identity or spelling is uncertain. The relationship after the name refers to the subject's relationship to John Wesley Hardin unless otherwise identified.
An, Doc J-cousin[?] may be an Anderson (see Parsons, Capture 34). Letters From: 1877 Oct 13[?]
Anderson, James (Jim)-cousin, was at the Waldrup ranch when Mrs. Waldrup told of Charles Webb's visit to arrest her son. Helped J.W. Hardin circulate pardon papers.(See Hardin vs. State 359, and Life 89) Letters From: 1892 Jul 17 Mentioned: 1877 Sep 9, Oct 26; 1879 Mar 2
Anglemiller, Joe-acquaintance in Austin. Mentioned: 1879 Apr 13
Anglin, Mrs. Mollie - The Andrew Anglin family made clothes on order and sold them through the Bowen store in the 1870s. (Parsons, Brown 26). They are listed in the 1880 census as living next door to Jane. Mentioned: 1881 Jul 3, Dec 14 1882 Jan 18
Ann-sister-in-law [?] Jane had an older sister named Ann (Parsons, Bowen 15) Mentioned: 1877 May 6, Sep 5
Armstrong, Lieut. John B.- one-time Texas Ranger who participated in capture of Hardin. Mentioned: 1879 May 11
Ashe, J.D. - District Clerk - Harris Co. Letters From: 1894 Mar 6, Aug 16, 23, Sept 20 Auguero, Louis – Client of J.W. Hardin Letters From: 1894 Oct 7 Auguero, Roman – Client of J.W. Hardin Letters From: 1894 Oct 7
Baker, D.(avid) P. - probably an inmate with Hardin in the Travis County jail. J. H. Clements writes him a letter on the back of a letter to Hardin. Mentions other names that are difficult to decipher or identify. Letter To: 1878, Feb 15
Barbisch, Joe – Austin Printing Co. Letters To: 1894 Nov 20 Barnett, Mary - cousin to John and Jennie Hardin.
Letter From: 1894 Oct 4. Barnette, R. E.-see Robert E. Hardin.
Bishop, F. D. - supporter of Hardin's pardon. Letters From: 1894 Apr 14
Bell, Tom - Sheriff - Hill Co.
Letters From: 1894 Mar 27, 30, Apr 14, Benny- perhaps Edward Bowen's brother and Joshua Bowen's son. Joshua mentions him in a letter to Edward Bowen,. Mentioned: 1879 Jul 2; 1880 Jul 15
Blackburn, M. – Client of J.W. Hardin Letters From: 1894 Oct 6 Blackshear, K.R. - Tax collector. Letters From: 1893 Jul 14(2); 1894 Feb 7 Letters To: 1894 Jan 9 Bond, F.[?] M.- addresses herself as Jane Hardin's sister. Letter From: 1888 May 22
Bowen, Beasley- Jane's half-brother, son of Neill and Purity Bowen. Mentioned: 1881 May 1
Bowen, Brown (Joshua) -brother-in-law, Jane's brother. Brown Bowen was hung for the murder of Thomas Haldeman in 1872. His father Neill Bowen asked Hardin to take responsibility for the murder but Hardin refused. Brown claimed Hardin was the guilty party even to the gallows. Mentioned: 1877, May 6, Aug 25, Oct 26, Dec 5, 20; 1878 Jan 31, Feb 15, Mar 14, 23, 26, Apr 19, May 18, 30, Jun 1
Bowen, Edna-Jane's half-sister, daughter to Neill and Purity Bowen. Mentioned: 1881 May 1
Bowen, Edward- Jane's cousin, son of Joshua Bowen. Letter From: 1880 Jul 13 [Copybook] Mentioned: 1877 May 6, 1879 Jul 2
Bowen, Elizabeth (Lizzie, Liza?)-sister-in-law, Janes older sister. Mentioned: 1877 Oct 26; 1878 Aug 19; 1879 Jul 22[?], 1881 Mar 5, May 1; 1882 Oct 4
Bowen, Joshua-Jane's uncle. Lives in Sadlers Mill, Gonzales County and is possibly the Josh in Santa Rosa, Florida. Letters From: 1880 Jul 15 Letters To: 1877 May 6 1878 Mar 23 [?], 1879 Jul 2 Mentioned: 1881 May 1; 1882 Feb 26
Bowen, Mattie (Mat, Martha, M. E, see also Mattie Odom)-Sister-in-law. Jane's sister. Becomes Mattie Odom December 1878) Letters From: 1877 Sep 5, Oct 26, Dec 20; 1878 Apr(May) 19, Jun 29, Aug 19 Mentioned: 1877 May 6, May 9; 1878 May 18, 30
Bowen, Neill (Neal)-Father-in-law, Jane's father. Letter From: 1882 Nov 26 Mentioned: 1877, May 6, Aug 25, Sep 12, Oct 26, Dec 5, 14, 20; 1878 Feb 15, Mar 14, 26, Apr 19, May 18, 2?, Jun 11, Aug 2, 19 1879 Jul 2, 22; 1881 Mar 5, May 1, Aug 14; 1889 Jul 14.
Bowen, Purity Ann Sunday-Neill Bowen's second wife, Jane's stepmother. Letter From: 1881 May 1 Mentioned: 1878 Aug 2
Bowen, William-brother-in-law, Jane's brother. Letters From: 1877 Oct 26 Mentioned: 1877 Dec 20; 1878 Apr 19
Bratton, B – Friend of J.W. Hardin Letters From: 1894 Oct 22 Brazell (Brassell) murders-Dr. Phillip Brassell and his son George were called from their beds on the night of September 19, 1876 and murdered by a group of men identified as members of the Sutton faction in the Sutton-Taylor feud. These murders aroused public outrage. The rangers were called in and eight men were arrested and charged. This is considered the last murder resulting from the long-running Sutton-Taylor feud. Mentioned: 1877 May 6, May 13
Brockius (Brosius), Doc-was in charge of the cattle that Hardin had gathered for a drive at the time of the Webb killing. Brockius was arrested and about to be lynched with Scrap Taylor and others when a member of the lynch mob helped him escape. Mentioned: 1877 Oct 26; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 May 25 Buchanan, John - County Clerk - Halletsville. Letters To: 1894 Aug 22 Burnet, Sally-acquaintance. Mentioned: 1889 Dec 8
Bush, Dr. - Prison doctor. Mentioned: 1885 Aug 26
Camel, Mary - see Campbell Campbell [?], Caroline- Jane's cousin. Mentioned in letter from Mattie Odom. Mentioned: 1879 Jun 15
Campbell, Charles-acquaintance of the Bowens, probably related. Mentioned: 1877, May 6
Campbell, Mary-Bowen relation. Writes from Santa Rosa, Florida Letters From: 1878 Mar 23, Mentioned: 1879 Jun 15
Campbell, Neal-with Hardin when he was captured on the train in Pensacola. Mentioned: 1877, Aug 25
Campbell, Sallie-Hardin knew her family in Sumpter and is reacquainted with her when he is in jail in Austin. Mentioned: 1878 Mar 14
Carnes (Karnes), Sheriff John-Sheriff of Comanche County when Webb killing occurred. Mentioned: 1877, Sep 9
Choate, Mr. of Karnes County-Mattie Hardin writes that Choate is a friend of Hardin's who wishes to help him in his legal troubles. Mentioned: 1877 Nov 26
Clements, Gip - cousin, Mannen's brother Mentioned: 1877, May 6, May 9; 1878 Feb 15, Oct 21; 1879 Mar 23, Jun 19
Clements, Jim- cousin, Mannen's brother. Married Annie Caroline, daughter of George and Amanda Jane Billings Tennille. Letters To: 1894 Oct 4 Mentioned: 1877 May 6, May 9; 1878 Feb 15[?], Oct 2, 1879 Jun 19; 1892 Jan 25
Clements, Joe [Joseph Hardin, Jo]-cousin, Mannen's brother. Married Sarah Jane, daughter of George and Amanda Jane Billings Tennille. February 1878 is in the Gonzales County jail awaiting trial. Letters From: 1878 Jan 31, Feb 15 Mentioned: 1877, May 6, May 9, Sep 9, 12, Oct 14; 1878 Oct 21; 1879 Mar 23, Jun 19, Aug 17
Clements, Manning [Emanuel, Mannen]. Cousin. Mother, Martha Balch Hardin, was sister to Hardin's father. The two were very close and helped each other out of various scrapes. Mannen Clements helped Hardin escape from the Gonzales County jail in 1872 when W. E. Jones was sheriff. Clements unsuccessfully tried to help Hardin escape from Huntsville. He was shot and killed in a saloon fight in 1887. Letters From: 1878 May 2?, Jun 1, Aug 3, 27, Oct 21; 1879 Mar 23 Letters To: 1879 May 11, 25, Jul 6, 27 (note), Aug 10 (note) Mentioned-1874, Sep 18; 1877, May 6, 9; 1878 Jan 19, Jan 31, Mar 14, Mar 17, 26, Jun 15, Jul 4, 14, Aug 2, Sep 11, 28, Oct 4, 22/27, Dec 3, 8, 23, 28; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 9, 23, Mar 2, Apr 13, 20, May 4, Jun 1, Jun 15, 19, Jul 6, 22, 30; Aug 10, Sep 21; 1880 May 27; 1881 Jun 1; 1884 Dec 7
Clements, Jr., Mannen (Mann)-Mannen Clement's son. Mentioned: 1878, May 2?, Jun 1, 27; 1879 Mar 23, May 25, Jun 1
Clements, Mollie, Mary A.-Mannen Clement's wife. Letters From: 1879 Mar 23 Mentioned: 1878, Jan 29, May 2?, Jun 1, 1879, Apr 13, 20, Jun 15[?], 19, Jul 6, 27, 30, Aug 10, Sep 21
Clements, Sallie-Mannen Clement's daughter. Married to Jim Miller. Mentioned: 1878 May 2?, Jun 1; 1879 Mar 23, May 4, 25, Jun 1, Sep 21
Clements, S. J. [Sarah Jane Tennille, Sallie] Daughter of George Tennille and Amanda Jane Billings, married Mannen's brother Joseph Hardin Clements. Letters From: 1879 Jun 19 Mentioned: 1879 Aug 17
Cloud, Mr.-Offers hospitality to Jane when she goes to Austin in 1878 to see Hardin in jail Mentioned: 1878 no date (mid August)
Cobb, Ben - Married to Jane's aunt Margaret, Neill Bowen's sister. Mentioned: 1877 May 6, Dec 20; 1879 Jun 15, Jul 2; 1882 Feb 26, Nov 26
Cobb, Bent-married to Lizzie Hardin Cobb? Mentioned: 1879 Sep 21
Cobb, J.B. "Buck"-Jane's cousin. Letters To: 1892 Sept 11, Nov 6; 1893 May 18 Mentioned: 1882 Sep 3
Cobb [?] Daisy,-possibly Jane's cousin, Margaret Cobb's daughter Mentioned: 1879 Jul 2; 1890 Apr 6,
Cobb, Lizzie (Sissie, Elizabeth)-sister. Letters From: 1877 undated; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 11 Mentioned: 1877 Sep 9, 15, Oct 26, Nov 21, 26, Dec 5; 1878 Jun 15, Aug 30, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24; 1882 May 25, Aug 13; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Aug 3
Cobb, Mary - mentioned in Purity's letter from Florida as a neighbor. Mentioned: 1881 May 1
Cobb, Margaret-Jane's aunt, Neill Bowen's sister, married to Ben. Letter From: 1879 Jul 2 Mentioned: 1879 Jun 15, 19; 1881 Apr 26; 1889 Dec 8
Cobb [?], Mollie-Probably Margaret Cobb's daughter Mary. Mentioned: 1879 Jul 2; 1882 Sep 3; 1889 Dec 8
Cobb, Mr.-brother-in-law, married to sister Lizzie. see Bent Cobb. Mentioned: 1879 Apr 27, May 4; 1882 May 25?
Cobb, Nannie-married Tony Tenille. Mentioned: 1877 May 6, Sep 5; 1889 Dec 8
Cobb, Sally (Sarah)-Jane Hardin's cousin. Daughter of Margaret and Ben. Mentioned: 1889 Dec 8
Colbey [sp?], F. A. - Hosts a ball in 1882 Mentioned: 1882 Mar 20 (invitation)
Coleman, R.R. – Ran for Sheriff of Gonzales Co. 1894 Letters To: 1894 Oct 14 Letters From: 1894 Oct 20, 21, Nov 2 Cooley, George-broken out of Lampasas County Jail with John Ringo. Mentioned: 1879 Apr 13
Corwin, Dennis-Sheriff of Travis County when Hardin is jailed there. Mentioned: 1878 Jan 31, Sep 16, 17, 24, Oct 4; 1879 Apr 13
Cresap, S.H. – Neighbor of J.W. Hardin Letters From: 1894 Nov 1 Cunningham, William-testified in Hardin's Comanche County trial that Hardin and his associates had conspired against Charles Webb. Mentioned: 1877, Oct 26
Denson, James M.-Mannen Clement's brother in law. Married his sister Mary Jane Rebecca Clements. Letters From: 1894 Oct 27 Mentioned: 1879 Mar 23
Denson, Mary Jane Rebecca Clements-cousin, Mannen Clement's sister. Mentioned: 1879 Mar 23
Diedrich, F. Letters From: 1894 Oct 29 Dikes, A. C.-cousin living in Eastland, Texas. Letters From: 1877 Dec 3
Dinkins, B. R.-sold cattle to Hardin (alias Swain) in Jacksonville, Florida. Letters From: 1876 May 2
Dixon, Jack-mentioned in Doc J An's letter Mentioned: 1877 Oct 10
Dixson, Ellack (Elec)-uncle, mother's brother living in Navarro County. Mentioned: 1879 Mar 2, Sep 21
Dixson, Mollie-Aunt, married to Elec Dixson? Mentioned: 1879 Sep 21
Dixson, Tom - Hardin's mother writes Dixson conspired with Cunningham to help kill Hardin on day Webb was killed. Mentioned: 1877 Oct 26
Dorst, Jim-friend from Gonzales. Mentioned: 1878 Jun 27
Doublin, Dell-acquaintance. Mentioned: 1879 Aug 17
Downing, L. M.-Meat vendor in Jacksonville, Florida who bought from Hardin as J. H. Swain. Letter To: 1876 Mar 23 Duncan, Jack-Dallas detective who assisted in the discovery of Hardin's whereabouts and his capture in Pensacola. Mentioned: 1877, Aug 25, Oct 10; 1878 May 2?,
Ed - Purity Bowen writes in a letter from Florida that Ed is in Sunday School. Mentioned: 1881 May 1
Ed-Hardin's mother Elizabeth writes that she is living with daughter Nannie and Ed (Nannie's Husband?) Mentioned: 1882 Aug 13
Ellis, Wadkin-see Wad.
Finley, R.W. - Comptroller of Public Accounts, State of Texas. Letters From: 1894 Apr ? Fleming, J. R.-Judge who presided over Hardin's Comanche County trial. Mentioned: 1877 Oct 26, Dec 5; 1878 Dec 3
Fleming, Mart-Comanche County citizen. Mentioned: 1878 Oct 20, Jul 6, 27
Fly & McNeal, atty.- Initiated petition to pardon J.W. Hardin from Cuero case. Letters From: 1892 Jan 8, 25, May 18, Letters To: 1893 Nov 5 Frank - Jane Hardin's sister?. Mentioned: 1877, May 6, Sep 5, 1878 Aug 19; 1879 Mar 16, May 13 1881 Mar 1, Apr 26, May 1, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26, May 28, Oct 4, Nov 26; 1886 May 2, Aug 3; 1888 May 22
Freeman, Pone-acquaintance of Bowens. Was subpoenaed as a witness in Brown Bowen's trial for the murder of Thomas Haldeman. Mentioned: 1879 May 13
Godfrey, John C.-cousin, offers support and money for Hardin's legal fees. Letter From: 1878 Apr 7 Letter To: 1878 Mar 15(26), Apr 7 Mentioned: 1878 Mar 14, Mar 17, Apr 29, May 2?
Gary, W.J. - wrote a poem for Hardins
Letters To: 1892 Oct 2 Gibbs, Barnett – Lawyer Letters From: 1894 Feb ? Gilbert Book Co. - Provided J.W. Hardin with law books.Sept 15, 28
Letters From: 1894 Glover, R.M. - Sheriff and friend of J.W.Hardin Letters From: 1894 Feb 28, Mar 28, 30, Apr 13, 16, Dec 1 Letters To: 1894 Mar 27, 30, Apr 14 Goree, Major Thomas J.-became superintendent of the Texas prison system in 1877. Mentioned: 1879 May 4 (note); 1880 Apr 24; 1885 Aug 26
Gray, Mr.-First husband of one of Elizabeth Hardin's Red River County neighbors. Mentioned: 1879 Apr 27
Grear, Mary Smith-mentioned in letter from Bright Smith's mother Mentioned: 1882 May 1
Grear, Will-Mentioned in letter from Bright Smith's mother. Mentioned: 1882 May 1
H, S. E.-Gives Jane $10 to help her get to Austin to visit Hardin in jail. Letters From: 1878 Aug ?
Haldeman, Tom (Halderman) -Murdered in 1872. Brown Bowen was hanged for his death on May 1878. Mentioned: 1878 Mar 14
Hall, Capt. Lee-Texas Ranger. Mentioned: 1879 May 11
Hardin, Aaron-cousin, son of Robert E. Hardin. Mentioned: 1877 Oct 14, Nov 26; 1878 Mar 15, Jul 6
Hardin, Alie B [Bell, Arabella]-sister-in-law. Married to brother, Jo Hardin who was lynched after the murder of Charles Webb in 1874. By 1880, Bell was married to her second husband, Mr. Pierce. Letters From: 1877 Sep 9 Mentioned: 1877 Sep 9, 15, undated; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 11; 1879 Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 May 25, Aug 13
Hardin, Barnett (W. B., Sr.) -Uncle, Polk County. Mentioned: 1877,undated[?]; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 30, Apr 7; 1879 Mar 2
Hardin, Dora-niece, daughter of Jo and Bell Hardin. Mentioned: 1882 May 25, Aug 13
Hardin [?], Elizabeth-Cousin [?], possibly daughter of Robert Hardin. Mentioned: 1877 May 9
Hardin, Elizabeth Dixon-Mother. Letters From: 1877 Sep 9, Oct 26, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, 26, Mar 30, May 30, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10; 1879 Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 May 27, Aug 30; 1882 May 25, Aug 13; Letters To: 1878 Dec 8; 1879 Jan 10 Mentioned: 1877, May 9, Sep 9, 12, 15, undated, Oct 14, Nov 21, 25, 26, Dec 3, Dec 5, 29; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 11, Jun 1, 2, 15, Jun 8, 23, Aug 2, 3, Oct 4, 20, 21, 27, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, Feb 23, Mar 3, Mar 23, Apr 13, May 4, 25; 1880 Apr 24; 1881 Jun 1; 1882 Feb 26, Apr 2; 1883 Jan 6; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 May 29 (funeral)
Hardin, Gippie [Barnett Gipson]- youngest brother. Mentioned: 1877, May 9, Sep 9, Oct 26, Nov 21, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, May 30, Jun 15, Jul 4, Jul 9, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24, May 27; 1882 May 25. Aug 13; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3, Sep 5; 1888 Feb 5,
Hardin, J.[ames] G.[ibson]. - Father, son of Benjamin Hardin and Martha Ann Barnett. He married Elizabeth Cartwright Dixon in 1847. They had eight children, five of whom reached maturity. Hardin was a Methodist circuit rider, a lawyer and a teacher. He died August, 1876. Letter To: -1874, Sep 18, 1874 Mentioned: 1877, May 9, Sep 9, Oct 26, undated, Dec 3, 14; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, Mar 30, Jun 2, Aug 30; 1882 Apr 2
Hardin, Jane Bowen (alias Jane Swain, Jennie) -Wife, married February 1872. Jane died November 6, 1892 while Hardin was still in prison. Letters To: 1876, (Thomasville, Ga), Sep. 8; 1877 May 6, 9, Jun 6, Aug 25, Sep 12, 16, Oct 14, 26, Dec 5, 14, 29; Nov 25; 1878 Jan 29, Mar 14, 17, 23, 26, Apr 29, May 18, 19, Jun 1, 2, 11, 15, 23, 27, 29, Jul 4, 14, Aug 2, 3, ?, 19, 27, 28, 31, Sep 11, 16, 17, 28, Oct 4, 10, 20, 21, 27, Nov 17, Dec 3, 8, ?, 28 1879 Jan 9, 10, 26, Feb 9, 23, Mar 2, 16, 23, Apr 13, 20, 27, May 4, 11 (note),13, 25, Jun 1, 15, 19, Jul 2, 6, 22, 27, 30, Aug 10, 17, Sep 21 (3), Nov 2; 1880 May 27, Aug 30; 1881 Mar 5, Apr 26, May 1, Jun 1, Jul 3, Aug 14, Sep 25, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26, Apr 2, May 25, 28, Aug 13, Sep 3, Oct 4; 1883 Feb 16; 1884 Jan 6, Dec 7; 1885 Sep 27, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3, Sep 5, Nov 7; 1887 Mar 27, Sep 4, Nov 6; 1888 Jan 22, Feb 5, Mar 25, May 22, Jun 24, Oct 7; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2; 1891 Apr 5, Oct 25;1892 Jan 4 Mentioned: 1877, Sep 9, 15, Oct 29, Nov 21, undated; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, Feb 26, Mar 11, Mar 30, May 30, Jun 8, Jul 9, Aug 16, 30; 1880 Apr 24, Jul 15; 1882 Aug 28Nov 26; 1886 Mar 7, May 2, Oct 3; 1887 Apr 3; 1889 May 5, Jul 14, Oct 20, Dec 8
Hardin, Jeff (Jefferson Davis)-brother. Mentioned: 1877, May 9, Sep 9, undated, Oct 26-27, Nov 21, 25, undated, Dec 14, 29; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, 26, May 30, Jun 8, Jul 4, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10, 20, Dec 28; 1879 Jan 10, Mar 2, 23, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24, May 27; 1882 May 25, Aug 13; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3
Hardin, Jennie (Callie, Jennie Martina, Jane)-daughter born in 1877. Letter of Jun 15, 1878 refers to the change of her name from Callie to Jane Martina. Letters To: 1886 May 2; 1887 May 1, Aug 28; 1889 Jul 14, Dec 8; 1892 Aug 28; 1893 Jun 30 Mentioned: 1878 Mar 17, May 30, Jun 8, 15, 27, Jul 9, Jul 14, Aug 30, Oct 20, Nov 17, Dec 3, 8; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Apr 20, 27, May 4, Jun 1, Jul 6, 30, Sep 21; 1881 Aug 14, Sep 25; 1882 Feb 26, May 25, Aug 13, Sep 3, Oct 1; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Mar 7, Aug 3, Sep 5, Oct 3, Nov 7; 1889 May 5, Oct 20; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2; 1891 Apr 5,
Hardin, Jodie-nephew, son of brother Joseph Hardin. Mentioned: 1877 Sep 9, 15; 1880 Aug 30, Aug 13
Hardin [?], John- Cousin[?], possibly son of Robert E. Hardin. Mentioned: 1877 May 9
Hardin, John Wesley-b. May 26, 1853 Letters From: 1874, Sep 18; 1876, May 12, Sep 8; 1877 Jun 6, Aug 25; 1878 Jan 29, Mar 14, 17, 26, Apr 29, May 18, Jun 2, 11, 15, 23, 27, Jul 4, 14, Aug 2, 28, 31, Sep 11, 16, 17, 28, Oct 4, 20, 27, Nov 17, Dec 3, 8, ?, 28; 1879 Jan 9, 10, 26, Feb 9, 23, Mar 2, 16, Apr 13, 20, May 4, 11, 25, Jun 1, Jul 6, 27, Aug 10, 17, Sep 21, Nov 2; 1881 Jun 1, Jul 3, Aug 14, Sep 25; 1882 Feb 26, Apr 2, Sep 3; 1884 Jan 6, Dec 7; 1885 Aug 26, Sep 27, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Mar 7, May 2, Sep 5, Oct 3, Nov 7; 1887 Mar 27, Apr 3, May 1, Aug 28, Sep 4, Nov 6; 1888 Jan 22, Feb 5, Mar 25, Jun 24, Oct 7; 1889 Feb 1, May 5, Jul 14, Oct 20, Dec 8; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2; 1891 Apr 5, Oct 25, Sept 11; 1892 Jan 4, Aug 21, 28, 30, Sept 11, Nov 6; 1893 Oct 29, Nov 5; 1894 Jan 1, Aug 22, Oct 4, 14. Letters To: 1875, Sep 26; 1876, Jan 24, 26, Mar 23, Apr 27, May 1, May 2, 12, 1877 May 9, Sep 9, 15, Undated, Oct 13, 26, 29, undated, Nov 21, undated, Nov 26, Dec 3, 5; 1878 Jan 15, 31, Feb 15 (2), 17, 26, Mar 11, 30, Apr 6, 7, 16, May 2?, 30, Jun 7, 8; 1891 Aug 4; 1892 Jan 8, Jan 25, May 18, Jul 5,Jul 17; 1894 Jan 28, Feb 28, Mar 6, 8, 28, 30, Apr 13, 14,16 28, May 9, 20, 23, Jun 22, Aug 4, 16, 23, Sept 1, 20, 28, Oct 4, 6, 7, 15, 21, 22, 28, 31, Nov 2. Dec 1, 30
Hardin, John Wesley, Jr.-son, B. August 3, 1875. Letters To: 1886 Mar 7; 1887 Apr 3; 1889 Oct 20; 1892 Aug 28. Mentioned: 1878 Mar 17, Jun 8, 15, 27, Jul 4, 14, Aug 30, Oct 20, Nov 17, Dec 3; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Apr 27, Jul 6, 30, Aug 17, Sep 21; 1881 Aug 14, Sep 25; 1882 Feb 26, May 25, Aug 13, Oct 1; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Sep 17, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, May 2, Aug 3, Sep 5, Oct 3, Nov 7; 1888 Oct 7; 1889 May 5, Jul 14, Dec 8; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2
Hardin, Joseph (Jo, Jodie)-brother, b. January 5, 1850. Lynched in retaliation for the killing of Charles Webb by John Wesley Hardin. Letters From: 1894 Jan 28 Mentioned: 1877 Oct 26, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Jan 15; 1879 Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 Apr 2; 1888 Jun 24; 1889 Jul 14,
Hardin, Mattie-sister. See Smith, Mattie Hardin
Hardin, Mattie [Martha] -cousin, daughter of Robert E. Hardin. Letter from: 1877 May 9, Sep 9, 12, Oct 14, 29, Nov 26; Mentioned: 1877, Sep 9, 15, Oct 26
Hardin, Mollie (Mary Elizabeth) -daughter, b. February 6, 1873. Letters To: 1880 Apr 24; 1882 Oct 4; 1886 Oct 3; 1889 May 5; 1891 Sept 11; 1892 Aug 21; 1893 Jun 30. Mentioned: 1877, May 9, Oct 14, 26, Dec 14; 1878 Mar 17, Jun 8, 15, 27, Jul 9, 14, Aug 30, Oct 4, 20, Nov 17, Dec 3; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Mar 16, Apr 27, May 4, 11, 25, Jun 1, 19, Jul 2, 6, 30, Aug 17, Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1881 Mar 5, Apr 26, Aug 14, Sep 25, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26, May 25, May 28, Aug 13, Sep 3, Oct 1; 1883 Feb 16; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Sep 27, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Mar 7, May 7, Aug 3, Sep 5, Nov 7; 1887 Apr 3; 1888 Feb 5, Oct 7; 1889 Jul 14, Oct 20, Dec 8; 1890 Nov 2
Hardin, Molly E.-cousin. Letters From: 1878 Jun 7
Hardin, Nannie-sister. Letters From: 1878 Jun 8, Jul 9, 1879 Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24; 1894 Oct 28 Letters To: 1879 Feb 23 Mentioned: 1877, May 9, Sep 9, Oct 26-27, Nov 21, 25, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Feb 15, 26, May 30, Jun 15, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10, 20, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 Feb 26, May 25, Aug 13; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3; 1888 Feb 5; 1891 Apr 5,
Hardin, Robert E. (Bob) [also R. E. Barnette, Marohn 104]-Uncle, brother to Hardin's father. Married Nancy Brinson Dixon. Living on a ranch in Brenham, Washington County, Texas. Helped harbor Hardin when he was on the run and with legal fees after he was captured. Letter From: 1877 May 9, Mentioned: Sep 9, 12, undated, Oct 26-27, 29, undated, Nov 26, Dec 5; 1878, Jan 15, Feb 15, Mar 17, Apr 6; 1879 Jul 6
Hardin, W. B. (Barnett)-cousin in Woodbury, Hill County. Letters From: 1878 Mar 15(26), Apr 6 Mentioned: 1877, Sep 9; 1878 Mar 14, Mar 15(26), 17, Apr 7, 19, May 2?; 1879 Jan 9, Jan 10, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1884 Dec 7
Hardin [?], Will-cousin. Robert Hardin's son? Mentioned: 1877 May 9
Hardy, Shep-friend. Hardin's logging partner. Was with Hardin when he was captured. Mentioned: 1877, Jun 6
Harison [Harrison?], James-acquaintance. Mentioned: 1878 May 2?
Hays, Captain Jack - Texas Ranger. Mentioned: 1879 Sep 21
Helm, Jack-leader of the Sutton faction. Member of the State Police and Sheriff of DeWitt County. Killed by Hardin and Jim Taylor in Cuero Mentioned: 1878 Jun 15
Hendricks, Ben (Captain)-Hotel keeper in Austin. Mentioned: 1878 no date (mid August), Sep 11; 1879 Apr 13
Hickock, Wild Bill (Heycoc)-Marshal of Abilene, Kansas. Mentioned: 1888 Jun 24
Hodge [?], Nelson-His case for attempted murder is mentioned by J. H. Clements in a letter to Hardin along with another name that cannot be deciphered. Mentioned: 1878 Feb 15
Homesley, Jim-Comanche County resident. Mentioned: 1878 Oct 20
Hogg, James A.- Governor of Texas (1891-1895) Letters To: 1892 Jan ?; 1893 Oct 29; 1894 Jan 1 Howell, E. - Friend of the Hardins